The Carleton Hodge collection: books from the library of Carleton Hodge Z7770 .H6
Lilly Library
- B (Box 28)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Savious Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible SocietyIn 4 vols. Only 1st vol has t.p. pages are continuously numbered., 1871 (Box 53)
    - 1. St. Matthew - St. Mark p. 180 (Box 53)
    - 2. St. Luke - St. John p. 181-382 (2 copies) (Box 53)
    - 3. Acts I - II Corinthians p. 383-612 (Box 53)
    - 4. Galatians I - Revelations p. 612-844 (Box 53)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1886 (Box 52)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1891 (Box 51)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1891 (Box 53)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1896 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. Potter's standard editions the new testament of our lord and saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the original Greek and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Chicago: Thompson & Thomas, [ca. 1905] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament narrative in the words of the sacred writers translated according to the vulgate with notes, maps, chronological and other tables. Eighteenth edition. London: St. Anselm's Society, 1912 (Box 37)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament a new translation by James Moffatt D.D., D. Litt. Yates professor of new testament Greek and Exegesis, Mansfield College, Oxford. New York: Hodder and Stoughton and George H. Doran Company, [1913?] (Date from a note by Hodge) (Box 26)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament a new translation by James Moffatt, D.D., Litt., M.A. (Oxon) together with the authorized version parallel edition with introduction. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, Publishers, 1922 (Box 25)
  - Bible. N.T. Shorter Bible the New Testament translated and arranged by Charles Foster Kent ... Third edition, revised. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1922 (Box 37)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1924 (date printed, and note by Hodge) (Box 51)
  - Bible. N.T. New covenant commonly called the new testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the Greek being the version set forth A.D. 1611 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1881 newly edited by the new testament members of the American revision committee A.D. 1900 standard edition. New York: Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated from the Latin Vulgate, ... and first published by the English College at Rheims, A.D. 1582 with annotations, references and an historical and chronological index. New York: Cincinnati: Chicago: San Francisco: Benziger Brothers, 1931 (Box 23)
  - Bible. N.T. Layman's New Testament being the Rheims text as first revised by Bishop Challoner edited with introduction & notes by Father Hugh Pope, O.P., S.T.M., D.S.S. New York: Sheed & Ward Inc., 1934 (Box 23)
  - Bible. N.T. National edition of the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ conformable to the edition of 1611 commonly known as the authorized or King James version. Philadelphia: National Bible Press, 1941 (Box 11)
  - Bible. N.T. National edition the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ conformable to the edition of 1611 commonly known as the authorized or King James version. Philadelphia: Gideons by the National Bible Press, 1943 (Box 11)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated into English from the original Greek by the very rev. Francis Aloysius Spencer, O.P. Edited by Charles J. Callan, O.P. and John A. McHugh O.P. New York: Macmillan Company, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament an American translation by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press(21st impression), 1946 (Box 22)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament and American translation by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1948 (Box 46)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament a translation in the language of the people by Charles B. William. Chicago: Moody Press, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ in eight 32-page portions, with over 500 illustrations and with 14 maps. New York: American Bible Society, [1953] (Box 6)
  - Bible. N.T. National edition the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ conformable to the edition of 1611 commonly known as the authorized or King James version. Philadelphia: Gideons by the National Bible Press, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Bible. N.T. New English bible New Testament. Cambridge: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Bible. N.T. New English bible New Testament. S.l.: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press(Printed in the United States of America)., 1962 (Box 6)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ Holy Land edition The words of our Lord printed in red ... New York: C. Wilderman Co., Inc., 1952 (Box 23)
  - Bible. N.T. Children's 'King James' Bible new testament. Evansville, IN: Modern Bible Translations, Inc., 1960 (Box 37)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ revised standard version with pictures. New York: American Bible Society, [1963] (Box 6)
  - Bible. N.T. New English bible New Testament second edition. S.l.: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press(Printed in the United States of America), 1970 (Box 6)
  - Bible. N.T. Saint Joseph edition of the New Testament of the new American Bible the New Testament translated from the original languages with critical use of all the ancient sources by members of the Catholic Bible Association of America ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Co., 1972 (Box 23)
  - Bible. N.T. Simple English Bible New Testament American edition. New York: International Bible Publishing Company, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Bible. N.T. New testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ with Psalms and Proverbs translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared commonly known as the authorized (King James) version. S.l.: Gideons International, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Bible. N.T. Gospels. Greek. Harmonies. 1885. [Harmony of the four gospels in Greek. Newly arranged, with explanatory notes, by Edward Robinson. Revised edition, ... additional notes by M.B. Riddle. Boston, New York: Houghton Mifflin(t.p. is missing. Information from OCLC) (Box 8)
  - Bible. N.T. Gospels. Harmonies. 1958. Knox. Gospel story: based on the translation of the four Gospels by Ronald Knox, arranged in a continuous narrative with explanations by Ronald Cox. New York: Sheed and Ward (Box 8)
  - Bible. N.T. New Testament of the Jerusalem Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1966 (Box 23)
  - Bible. N.T. Greek-English New testament. Third Printing. Washington, D.C.: Christianity Today, 1976 (Box 32)
  - Bible. N.T. Original New Testament Edited and translated from the Greek by the Jewish historian of Christian beginnings Hugh J. Schonfield. San Francisco: Harper & Row, (Cambridge, Hagerstown, New York, Philadelphia, London, Mexico City, Sao Paulo, Singapore, Sydney), 1985 (Box 32)
  - Bible. N.T. Matthew. Gospel according to Saint Matthew: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1897 (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Matthew. Gospel according to St. Matthew: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, [1910] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Matthew. New testament {text in Hebrew} containing the record of the new covenant with the House of Israel and the House of Judah. Revised by the revision committee of the Hebrew Christian Alliance. Chicago: Hebrew Christian Alliance of America, 1940 (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Mark. Gospel according to Saint Mark: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1910 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. Mark. Gospel of St. Mark a new translation in simple English from the Nestlé Greek text by Edward Vernon. New York: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1952 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. Luke. Gospel according to Saint Luke: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. By his majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London: British and Foreign Bible Society printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode, [ca. 1920s?] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. John. Gospel according to Saint John: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1885 (Box 53)
  - Bible. N.T. John. Emphasized gospel of John. Sixth million. Framingham, MA: Miss Elizabeth Merriam, [ca. 1920?] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. John. Gospel according to Saint John. New York: American Bible Society, [1942?] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. John. Revelation of John. Translated by Richard Lattimore. New York: Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 1962 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. John. Gospel according to John the new international bible. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Bible Publishers, 1973 (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Acts. Acts of the apostles: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, [1913?] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Acts. Acts of the apostles: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society Printed for Massachusetts Bible Society, Boston, 1913 (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Acts of the apostles translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised by his majesty's special command appointed to be read in churches. London: British Foreign Bible Society printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode, Ltd., [ca. 1920-1940?] (Box 56)
  - Bible. N.T. Acts. Good news in action the acts of the apostles from the new testament in today's English version. Third edition. New York: American Bible Society, 1971 (Box 55)
  - Bible. N.T. Revelation of St. John the divine: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London: British Foreign Bible Society printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode, [ca. 1920s?] (Box 56)
  - Bible of the sick from the French of Frederic Ozanam. New York: Christian Press Association Publishing Company, 1901 (Box 55)
  - Bílek, František. Chvála svaté lásky. Brno: "Zvlášstní vydání", 1992 (Box 36)
  - Book of proverbs from the authorized King James version with an introduction by Robert Gordis and decorations by Valenti Angelo. New York: Heritage Press, 1963 (Box 55)
  - Brandt, Leslie F. Epistles / now. St. Louis: Concordia Publishing House, 1976 (Box 55)
  - Bread of life the gospel of John New King James version gospel notes for witnessing and Christian living. Bradenton, FL: Bible Alliance, Inc., 1982 (Box 56)
  - Burton, Ernest de Witt. and Edgar Johnson Goodspeed. Harmony of the synoptic Gospels in Greek. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, c1920, ninth impression, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Burton, Ernest de Witt. and Edgar Johnson Goodspeed. Harmony of the synoptic Gospels in Greek. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, c1920 and 1947, fourteenth impression, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Burton, Ernest de Witt. Records and letters of the Apostolic age the new testament Acts, Epistles, and Revelation in the version of 1881 arranged for historical study. Eleventh edition. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1909 (Box 55)
- C (Box 55)
  - Cambridge history of the Bible the west from the reformation to the present day. Edited by S.L. Greenslade, F.B.A. Cambridge: University Press, 1963 (Box 28)
  - Clark, George W. New harmony of the four gospels in English, according to the common version. Arranged with explanatory notes, brief description of customs, words, names, ... Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1870 (entered as an act of congress 1870) (Box 46)
  - Codex Alexandrinus (Royal Ms. 1 D v-viii) in reduced photographic facsimile Printed by order of the Trustees sold at the British Museum and ... Oxford: University Press, 1915-1975 (Box 29)
    - Old testament part I Genesis - Ruth, 1915 (Box 29)
    - Old testament part II 1 Samuel - 2 Chronicles, 1930 (Box 29)
    - Old testament part III Hosea - Judith, 1936 (Box 29)
    - Old testament part IV I Esdras - Ecclesiasticus, 1957 (Box 29)
  - Cohen, Mortimer J. Pathways through the bible. Philadelphia: Jewish Publication Society of America, 1968 (Box 55)
  - Combined Gospels of Matthew, Mark, Luke and John. Russell Hubbard White, comp., arr., publ. Boston: Russell Hubbard White2 copies: 1 gilt edges; 2 dj & red edges., 1947 (Box 8)
  - Complete sayings of Jesus the King James version of Christ's own words without interpolations and divested of the context, ... assembled and arranged in sequence by Arthur Hinds ... Philadelphia and Toronto: John C. Winston Company, 1955 (Box 37)
  - Concise Gospel and the Acts. Christopher J. Christianson comp. Plainfield, N.J.: Logos International, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Copenhagen Haggadah Altona-Hamburg, 1739 The artist: Uri Pheibush son of Isa Eisik Segal Facsimile edition introduction by Chaya Benjamin (title information from insert about the book, publisher information printed in book.) New York: Rizzoli International Publications, 1986 (Box 29)
  - Coutler, Frederick R. Harmony of the gospels in modern English: The Life of Jesus Christ. Monterey, CA: York Publishing Company, 1974 (Box 7)
- D (Box 7)
  - Dale, Alan T. Winding quest the heart of the old testament in plain English. New York: Morehouse-Barlow Co., 1973 (Box 55)
  - Davidson, Benjamin. Analytical Hebrew and Chaldee lexicon.: Every word and inflection of the Hebrew old testament arranged alphabetically and with grammatical analysis ... Grand Rapids, MI: Regency Reference Library Zondervan Publishing House, 1970 (Box 41)
  - De Vinck, José. Words of Jesus with key readings from new and old testaments translated from the Greek. Allendale, N.J.: Alleluia Press, 1977 (Box 46)
  - Dictionary of the Targumim, the Talmud Babli and Yerushalmi, and the Midrashic literature compiled by Marcus Jastrow, Ph.D. Litt. D. with an index of scriptural quotations. Brooklyn, N.Y.: P. Shalom Pub, Inc., 1967 (Box 41)
    - Vol. I (Box 41)
    - Vol. II (Box 41)
- E (Box 41)
  - Elkins, R. William. Song of songs. New York: Washington: Hollywood: Toronto: Vintage Press, 1956 (Box 55)
  - English harmony of the four evangelists, generally disposed after the manner of the Greek of William Newcome, archbishop of Armagh: ... Philadelphia: Published by Kimber and Conrad, 1809 (Box 8)
  - Epitome Historiæ Sacræ, auctore Lhomond. Editio nova prosodlæ signis vocumque interpretatione adornata. Baltimore: Printed and Published by Kelly, Hedian & Piet, 1859 (Box 56)
- E (Box 56)
  - Fitzmyer S.J., Joseph A. Wandering Aramean collected Aramaic essays. Ann Arbor, MI: Edwards Bros., Inc.(Series title on pg. across from t.p. Society of Biblical Literature Monograph series. ... No. 25), 1979 (Box 42)
  - Four Gospels and the Acts of the Apostles in the authorized version. Oxford: Oxford University Press and London: Humphrey Milford, [ca. 1930?] (Box 56)
  - Four prophets Amos • Hosea • First Isaiah • Micah a modern translation from the Hebrew by J.B. Phillips. New York: Macmillan Company, 1963 (Box 55)
- G (Box 55)
  - Genuine Epistles of the Apostolical fathers; St. Barnabas, St. Ignatius, St. Clement, St. Polycarp, the Shepherd of Hermas, and the martyrdoms of St. Ignatius and St. Polycarp, written by those who were present at their sufferings. ... First American from the third London edition. New York: Printed and Published by Southwick and Pelsue, 1810 (Box 56)
  - Gill D.D., John. An exposition of the Old Testament: in which are recorded the origin of mankind, of the several nations of the world, and of the Jewish nation in particular: the lives of the patriarchs of Israel: ... in six volumes. Philadelphia: Printed by William W. Woodward, 1817 (Box 24)
    - v.1 (Box 24)
    - v.2 (Box 24)
    - v.3 (Box 24)
  - God's Bible an epochal revelation sponsored by God's angels Part IV, Papers 120-196 The life and teachings of Jesus. [S.l.]: Pathways, Inc., [1995?] (Box 30)
  - Goodman, Philip. Hanukkah anthology. Philadelphia: Jerusalem: Jewish Publication Society, 1992 (Box 27)
  - Gospel of Jesus Vicenza: Edizioni Istituto S. Gaetano, 1970 (Box 56)
  - Gospel of Jesus Vicenza: Edizioni Istituto S. Gaetano, 1970 (Box 56)
  - Gospel treasury and extraordinary harmony of the four evangelists. The text in the words of the authorized version, arranged according to Greswell's harmonia evangelica. with analytical introductions; scripture illustrations; notes, selected from the most approved commentators; practical reflections; ... compiled by Robert Mimpriss. Second edition. New York: Dodd & Mead, Publishers, [ca. 1965] (date from Hodge note in front cover, also at bottom of pg. vii) (Box 7)
  - Gospels of Saint Matthew, Saint Mark, Saint Luke & John together with the Acts of the apostles according to the authorized King James version with reproductions of religious paintings in the Samuel H. Kress collection arranged and printed by Richard Ellis for the Samuel H. Kress Foundation. New York: Samuel H. Kress Foundation, 1959 (Box 29)
  - Green, William Henry. Higher criticism of the Pentateuch. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1902 (Box 28)
- H (Box 28)
  - Harper, William R. Hebrew word lists to accompany "Hebrew Vocabularies" Chicago: American Publication Society of Hebrew, 1884 (Box 35)
  - Heart of the Bible its promises. Cleveland, OH: Edwards & Franklin Co., 1927 (Box 37)
  - Heim, Ralph Daniel. Harmony of the Gospels for students. Philadelphia: Muhlenberg Press, 1947 (Third Printing) (Box 8)
  - Hertz, Dr. Joseph H. Authorized daily prayer book revised edition Hebrew text, English translation with commentary and notes. New York: Bloch Publishing Company, 1959 (Box 27)
  - Hinkle, John Ray. Our salvation bible. [S.l.]: John Ray Hinkle, 1954 (Box 56)
  - His great apostle the life and letters of Paul using the text of the American standard revised bible. Prepared by Sydney Strong, William E. Barton Theodore G. Soares ... Chicago and New York: Hope Publishing Company, 1906 (Box 56)
  - His life a complete story in the words of the four Gospels prepared by William E. Barton, Theodore G. Soares, Sydney Strong using the text of the American standard revised bible. Chicago and New York: Hope Publishing Company, 1940 (Box 56)
  - Huck, Albert. Synopsis of the first three gospels. Albert Huck Ninth edition. Revised by Hans Lietzmann English edition by F.L. Cross. New York: American Bible Society, [1954?] (Box 55)
- I (Box 55)
  - Interwoven gospels and gospel harmony the four histories of Jesus Christ blended into a complete and continuous narrative in the words of the Gospels, with a complete interleaved harmony ... compiled by Rev. William Pittenger ... seven thousand. New York: Fords, Howard & Hulbert, 1893 (Box 37)
- J (Box 37)
  - James, Fleming. Hale lectures personalities of the Old Testament. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1939 (Box 27)
  - Jefferson, Thomas. Life and morals of Jesus of Nazareth extracted textually from the Gospels in Greek, Latin, French and English. Washington: Government Printing Office, 1904 (Box 8)
  - Jesus the four gospels, Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John, combined in one narrative and rendered in modern English. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1973 (Box 46)
  - Job for the modern man today's English version. New York: American Bible Society, 1971 (Box 56)
  - Johnson, Allan Chester, ed. John H. Scheide biblical papyri Ezekiel. Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Jordan, Clarence. Cotton patch version of Paul's epistles. New York: Koinonia Publication Association Press, 1968 (Box 56)
- K (Box 56)
  - Knopf, Carl Sumner. Old Testament Speaks. New York: Thomas Nelson and Sons, 1933 (Box 27)
  - Koinonia "Cotton Patch" version. Americus, GA, Clarence L. Jordan, 1963-1969 (Box 56)
    - A Letter to the Christians in Atlanta or First Corinthians(2 copies), 1968 (Box 56)
    - A Second Letter to the Christians in Atlanta or the Second Corinthiansand (2 editions), 1963; 1968 (Box 56)
    - Letters to -- The Georgia Convention (Galatians) and to the Alabaster African Church (Box 56)
    - Smithville, Alabama (Philippians)and (2 editions), 1966; 1968 (Box 56)
    - Letter to God's people in Columbus (Colossians) and Selma (I & II Thessalonians), 1968 (Box 56)
    - Letters to young Christains (I & II Timothy and Titus)(2 copies), 1967 (Box 56)
    - Letter to the Hebrews or A first-century manual for church renewal(2 copies), 1963 (Box 56)
    - Letters from partners Rock, Jack & Joe I & II Peter; I, II, III John & Jude(2 copies), 1969 (Box 56)
    - Letters to Ephesians and Philemon(2 copies), 1968 (Box 56)
- L (Box 56)
  - Lattimore, Richmond. Four gospels and the revelation newly translated from the Greek. New York: Washington Square Press published by Pocket Books, 1981 (Box 56)
  - Lipsky, Abram. Nārrātiōnēs biblicae from the vulgate by Abram Lipsky ... and Harry E. Wedeck ... New York: Newark: Boston: Chicago: San Francisco: Silver, Burdett and Company, 1928 (Box 56)
  - Looman, T.M. Handboek der Bijbelverklaring voor huisgezinnen; de voornaamste gedeelten der heilige schrift in geschiedkundigen zamenhang uitgelegd, ... derde deel. Oude testament: van rehabeam tot aan den ondergang van het Rijk van Israël. Te Amsterdam: Bij H. Höveker(Series title? Christelijke Huis-Bibliotheek. III. Pg. opposite of t.p.), 1855 (Box 38)
- M (Box 38)
  - MacKnight, James. New literal translation, from the original Greek of all the apostolical epistles. With a commentary, and notes, philological, critical, explanatory, and practical. To which is added, a history of the life of the apostle Paul. A new edition, to which is prefixed, an account of the life of the author. New York: M.W. Dodd, 1850 (Box 20)
  - McFayden, John Edgar. Wisdom books (Job, Proverbs, Ecclesiastes) also Lamentations and the Song of Songs in modern speech and rhythmical form. Second edition. London: James Clarke & Co., [ca. 1920] (Box 56)
  - Mertens-Fonck, Paule. Glossary of the Vespasian Psalter and hymns Pt. One -- the verb. Paris: Société d'Édition, 1960 (Box 2)
- N (Box 2)
  - Nave's topical bible a digest of the holy scriptures more than twenty thousand topics and subtopics, and one hundred thousand references to the scriptures, embracing all doctrines of biblical religion, and all phases of ancient society history, ... Nashville, TN: Southwestern Company, 1962 (Box 48)
- O (Box 48)
  - Old testament pseudepigrapha. Edited by James H. Charlesworth. New York, London, Toronto, Sydney and Auckland: Doubleday, 1983-1985 (Box 46)